

#### Profile

Experienced and reliable IT professional with over six years of experience working in a wide-range of enterprises to ensure the optimal performance of their application systems using automation and cloud technologies. Adept in providing solutions to improve and enhance services within a devops framework. Bringing forth a growth mindset and seeking to find the best path forward for the users.

"Look for the good in every situation, seek the valuable lesson in every setback, look for the solution to every problem. Think and talk continually about your goals."

-Brian Tracy

## Employment History

#### Infrastructure Automation Engineer at Boys Town, Omaha

December 2019 — Present

- Created reliable automated workflows for service delivery of VMs and applications using vRealize Automation, Rundeck, and Powershell.
- Helped develop Azure cloud app deployment pipeline for integration with the CI/CD pipeline web applications.
- Improved Splunk infrastructure.
- Improved VMware automated infrastructure.
- Spearheaded integration of vRealize into ServiceNow.
- Improved containerization infrastructure, formerly under OpenShift and shifting to PKS.
- Created automation scripts in Javascript, Python, Bash and Powershell.
- Lead an architecture guild made up of stakeholders, developers, security and operations to create a path for cohesive IT solutions which impact the business.

#### **DevOps Engineer at Proxibid, Omaha**

October 2018 — November 2019

- Designed and improved a CI/CD pipeline for web applications featuring a suite of tools that includes Jenkins, Nexus, Docker, Rancher, Ansible, VMware and AWS.
- Managed and improved existing high-availability, scalable architecture in AWS.
- Managed network security of web applications through Palo Alto and certificate management.
- Developed and improved unified monitoring dashboards and metrics scripts which channeled into Datadog and Nagios. Automated deployment and configuration of agents.
- Developed and managed websites on Wordpress platform for hundreds of customers.
- Managed VMware resources and ESXi host.

#### **Details**

partofaplan@gmail.com

#### Links

LinkedIn

Github

DockerHub

#### **Skills**

Linux/Unix

**Computer Systems** 

DevOps

Amazon AWS

Docker

Computer Networking

 Managed and improved Atlassian infrastructure. Improved underlying security.

#### Systems Engineer at Northrop Grumman, Omaha

March 2017 — October 2018

Worked on Offutt AFB for the 557th WW.

- Created automated deployment of application servers using Ansible.
- Developed and improved scripts for configuring and patching middleware, Glassfish, WebLogic and Apache web servers using Perl and Bash.
- Troubleshot runtime issues with Java applications running on the web application servers. Improved application platform performance and security.
- Managed and improved Splunk infrastructure.
- Managed and improved Atlassian Infrastructure.
- Developed new monitors for capturing key performance metrics in Nagios.
- Participated in security audits of core applications and provided DoD with comprehensive documentation on application platform security.
- Performed load testing for applications using JVM and jMeter tools.
- Migrated strategic platform software to AWS cloud and improved platform performance.

#### Systems Engineer - Data Analytics at Concentric Corporation, Omaha

November 2016 — January 2017

Contracted to Mutual of Omaha

- Managed SAS and Tableau systems.
- Upgraded SAS system.
- Surveyed users for improvements to the system.

#### Systems Engineer at Northrop Grumman, Omaha

August 2015 — November 2016

Job duties are same as in most recent Northrop Grumman position. I left NG to pursue another contract opportunity and was re-hired after the contract was terminated.

#### Service Desk Analyst at Stefanini, Omaha

March 2015 — July 2015

Contracted to First Data Corp.

- Took internal customer ticket for desktop and hardware related service issues.
- Resolved service issues through phone, chat and email.
- Improved processes by developing automated scripts for driver updating, printer connectivity and disk de-fragmentation.

#### Client Account Services Associate at Aerotek, Omaha

October 2014 — March 2015

#### Contracted to TD Ameritrade

- Database entry into internal CRM system.
- Verified customer paperwork for accuracy of data.

Participated in process improvement through LEAN team management.

#### Customer Experience Specialist at LinkedIn, Omaha

August 2007 — July 2014

- Resolved customer tickets via chat and email.
- Received technical escalation tickets and resolved them. Those I
  could not resolve I identified as bugs in JIRA and forwarded to the
  engineering team.
- Participated in process improvement groups.
- Trained new customer experience specialists in identifying technical issues.

### Education

### Associate's, General Studies, Metropolitan Community College (NE), Omaha

October 2012 — October 2014

# Bachelor's of Science, Cloud Computing, Western Governors University, Omaha

October 2017 — October 2021

## Certifications

#### CompTIA, Omaha

Security+, A+, Network+, Project+, Cloud Essentials

ITIL, Omaha

**Foundations** 

### ■ References

References available upon request

## Highlighted Projects

#### Proxibid - Dockerized AI Machine Learning Application

July 2019 — August 2019

The Raikes school at UNL worked with Proxibid to have interns build a machine learning application using TensorFlow and other modules. This application looked at different images and then tagged them based on categories. I was able to Dockerize the front-end which used Node.js.

# Proxibid - Automated Deployment of Monitoring Agents Across On-Prem/Cloud Resources

February 2019 — April 2019

I created Ansible playbooks which were used to deploy Datadog agents for customized application and host monitoring on on-prem and cloud resources. I also did this with Nagios XL agents.

### Northrop Grumman - Created Automation for Deploying Glassfish Servers and Custom Java Apps

April 2017 — February 2018

Using Ansible, I created playbooks that were used to package a Java application using Maven, check it into a repository for scanning and safely deploy it to Oracle Glassfish and WebLogic servers.

# Boys Town - Created Automated Workflows to Full Deploy MSSQL with Windows Server Hosts

February 2020 — September 2020

I built out the necessary workflows and scripts for 1) creating a Windows Server with all the necessary SAN disks and 2) autoinstall and configure MSSQL on the server, using vRealize and Powershell.

# Personal - Building Node.js Projects and a Containerized Deployment Environment for Various Cloud Environments

October 2020 — October 2020

Coded a simple Next.js (Node.js base) dynamic website at https://github.com/partofaplan/znjsp. The goal is to get better at coding in Node.js and learn how to utilize continuous deployment with container solutions. The app currently pushes the code to DockerHub at partofaplan. I am testing different cloud providers (like Azure) for webhook integration as well.